Prophet T.B. Joshua is led by the Holy Ghost to pray for visitors to The SCOAN from all over the globe in the name of Jesus Christ.
Whatever barrier, affliction or challenge they were facing melted like wax before the Lord of hosts
at the mention of the name Jesus Christ in prayer.
As the ministration continued, surprisingly, this woman sprang from her seat,
moments before the man of God got to her, and started running away across the auditorium.
Let's find out why.
We'll kill everyone here.
Who are you?
Ancestors.
What have you done to her ?
I will kill that husband; I will kill her husband.
What have you done to her marriage?
Which marriage? There is no marriage.
What have you done to her career?
Which career?
I have destroyed this lady; I have destroyed her.
She will kill you. This lady - she will kill you. Just leave here; leave here right now.
Breaking whatever chain the devil had used to bind this woman to himself,
Prophet T.B. Joshua set her free by the power of the Holy Ghost.
As she was declared free, she was helped to her feet
and began to rejoice in the freedom that comes from deliverance.
TESTIMONY TIME
People of God, Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
Emmanuel!
Thank you. My name is Yvonne Rapati from Johannesburg, South Africa.
The man standing next to me is my lovely husband, Gideon Rapati.
He is also from South Africa. Thank you.
The problem that brought me here was setback and the need for financial breakthrough.
I didn't know that I had spirits in me.
But then I was born into a family that worships idols.
From both families - from my father's side and from my mother's side.
So, last week I was delivered from all those spirits.
When Prophet T.B. Joshua was praying for the people in the church,
he came to the altar and prayed for me.
Oh my God. I didn't know that one day, I would be the one manifesting.
I used to tell my husband, "When I go to The SCOAN, I will never do such things".
I was surprised when I was seeing myself manifesting, fighting.
I thank God that the man of God delivered me from all the spirits.
The spirit of anger cost me a lot because every time my husband was trying to talk to me,
was trying to have a conversation with me, I was ready to fight all the time.
I was ready to defend all the time.
And I didn't know what I was defending myself for.
I remember one day, when I went to the hairdresser, my husband came late to fetch me.
Some other ladies were there.
They were telling me some issues about my husband, what he was doing there.
They said that my husband was dating someone in the saloon.
I just kept quiet.
When he came to fetch me, we went back to the house.
When we were driving home, I asked him about this issue. He refused to answer me.
My God, that spirit of anger came whilst he was driving.
I don't know what happened, but I jumped.
I grabbed the steering wheel, I turned the steering wheel while the car was moving.
He was driving 120 mph, and the car over turned.
Then, I went for the gun because my husband is a policeman in South Africa.
What I was trying to reach was a gun.
The spirit in me wanted me to kill him.
So I went for the gun.
When I tried to grab the gun, the gun fell down. So I opened the door.
My husband just opened the door and ran.
I grabbed that gun. I left the car there while the ignition was still on.
So, I just left the car there, in the middle of the road. I went back home
I was just trekking. I was walking.
My husband went straight to the police station.
He went there to report me that I wanted to shoot him.
Then, the policemen came - there were 4 of them.
By then I was in the house.
When they came, I quickly grabbed the gun and pointed the gun at them.
I said, "If any one of you comes near me, I will show you today. I will shoot you to death".
So three of them ran; they ran back.
My husband also ran back.
One of the policeman came to me. He said, "You know what, sister, please calm down!
I just want to speak to you. Calm down!"
So I managed, I don't know how I managed to calm down.
Then he said to me, "Give me the gun".
I said, "You know what? Talk whatever you want to talk, I'm not giving you this gun.
I want to shoot that husband of mine today. I want to kill him today".
The policeman said to me, "Please put the gun down. Let us speak.
We are here to speak to you, we are not here to arrest you".
I managed to give the policeman that gun.
Then my husband came in.
Then my husband said to them, "I don't want to talk to her nor to anyone.
What I'm here for is to take my clothes. I'm moving out of this house".
I was happy to hear that.
Then my husband went straight to the bedroom.
He took all his clothes. Then all of them went away.
I was just happy to own the house because I was the man of that house.
I was the one who gave instructions all the time. I was always screaming and fighting.
I never showed my husband and my children love.
Especially my ten-year-old daughter. She said that I was always beating her without skipping a day.
I've got three children.
The first one is the mother of the other two
because all the time, when they wanted something, they wouldn't come to me.
They would go straight to their father, "Father, please give us food. Give us this".
When they came to me, I would beat them - all of them.
I was always fighting in the house. I was always causing problems.
I was looking for problems all the time. I never had peace.
I never knew that this day, today, would come.
I never knew that one day I would sit with my husband and we would have a conversation.
Or sit with my husband and smile at him or talk to him.
I thank the prophet, Prophet T.B. Joshua, for this day.
Madam, you said that this spirit made you the man of the house.
Can you describe the things that you were instructing your husband to do,
that ordinarily a wife was supposed to do.
What were some of those things you were pushing him to do?
As husband and wife...
When you are staying together, you have to meet as husband and wife.
But in my house, there were instructions. I would only meet with him when I wanted.
At my workplace, I work 7 days in, 7 days out.
When I was working that week, the full seven days he was not allowed to touch me.
He was not allowed to come near me.
Every time he would be begging me, "Please come to sleep".
I would just say, "Okay. Go to sleep. I'm coming right now".
I would just leave my husband to go to sleep,
and then around 2:00 am, I would go to bed slowly so that he wouldn't touch me.
The minute he would wake up and say, "Why are you doing this?", fighting again. I was ready to attack.
I was always fighting him.
This spirit has affected my life a lot.
I didn't even cook in the house. He was the one who was doing the house chores.
He was the one who was cooking. He was the one who was bathing the children.
He was the one who was doing everything. I was always tired.
When he had cooked and I came home from work,
he would say, "I've already cooked. Just dish up".
I would say, "Okay. I'm coming right now". I would go straight to the bathroom, take my shower.
After that - gone!
I didn't dish up for him. I didn't dish up for my kids.
So these spirits have affected my life a lot.
Sister, can you tell us, last week as Prophet T.B. Joshua was moving around...
You had told your husband that when you come to The SCOAN, you are not going to manifest. Nothing would happen.
Describe to us what happened last week, as the prophet began to move around and pray for people.
Okay. When the prophet was touching everyone, I was just look around,
saying to myself, "These people, I wonder what they are doing - manifesting and doing all that".
I was just wondering, "What's going on?"
The minute the prophet came to the altar - I was sitting there at the back of the altar -
when he came near me, he never even touched me.
When he came closer, something just came into me, "Run away!". I was just shaking.
I ran away. I was surprised at seeing everybody around me.
Everybody was surrounding me. I was just surprised, "What's going on?"
That was how the evil spirit within our sister was exposed.
It tried to cause her to run away but the power of God took control as we can see.
That's how that spirit was confessing what it had caused in her life.
Tell us, sister, to the glory of God, ever since that touch, what are the changes that you've seen in your life?
Before that, when Prophet T.B. Joshua was touching everyone,
when he lifted up his hand - wham!
I saw something. The hand was very huge!
When he did 'wham', I said to myself, "I'm not here for this, I'm running away for my life.
He's going to kill me". That hand was very huge.
When I looked at him in his eyes, I saw flames. I saw fire in his eyes, so that's why I ran away.
Ever since that touch...
I never knew that one day, I would smile at my husband.
He had never in his life saw me smiling, talking to him nicely.
It wasn't easy for me to say 'sorry', but since we came to the SCOAN,
everything he says or every time I've wronged him, I would say, "I'm sorry".
I thank God for my life. I thank God for this.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
This is the confirmation of our sister's deliverance and we all heard what she said earlier.
She said that even before coming to The SCOAN, she told her husband that if we get there, nothing will happen to me.
I'm not going to manifest like others. Even as Prophet T.B. Joshua was moving around, she was just observing,
thinking to herself that nothing would happen, she would never fall.
But we saw at that touch, everything changed, and that evil spirit was exposed and deliverance came.
So at this point, we want to listen to your husband - a few words.
We believe he's in a position to shed more light on the experiences in the past.
Sir, you're welcome. Please introduce yourself to us.
Children of God, Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
Emmanuel!
Indeed, God is with us.
My name is Mr Gideon Rapati.
And the beauty standing beside me is my lovely wife, Mrs Yvonne Rapati.
I am a police officer in South Africa, in my country
and also a subject matter expert on issues of domestic violence.
Mr Gideon Rapati
Police Officer, South Africa
I have been taken away from doing operational duties at the police station in our state,
and I was taken straight to the training division of the South African police.
I facilitate exactly this type of intervention - domestic violence learning program -
to both my colleagues and all the people within my jurisdiction,
within the cluster that we are serving.
So, my life feels like a very long life.
The 12 years that I have spent with my wife feel like 50 years of my life.
But with the grace of God I endured.
Mr Gideon Rapati & Wife
Deliverance Testimony
Children of God, I have experienced the life of long-suffering.
My wife has already said most of the things that I'm going to say.
When I met my wife, she was very down-to-earth.
You can see how beautiful she is; any man would want to settle with her.
We met and within a week's time of knowing each other...
I was staying in police barracks at a male dormitory,
where I was not even allowed to bring a woman in.
But I started sneaking her in.
Within a month, my wife had already moved in with me in that barracks.
I had to totally disregard all the visits from the officials
who frequently came to see if there was anything that we were doing that we were not supposed to do.
I fell in love with my wife, who was a very good woman then.
But from there, we started having a little argument there, and fights there.
We had already moved in together by then, when she said to me,
"Mr Rapati, I can't stay with you. Where I come from, they would never allow this.
You must go and introduce yourself. You must go and pay the bride price".
So everything between my wife and I happened quickly.
I'm saying the events were happening in a quick succession.
Personally, I have never really got to know her and her purpose in my life.
What happened between me and my wife...
We had our first child; our daughter is now 11 years old.
Immediately after we had a child together, my wife started calling all the shots.
I became a puppet. My wife became my puppet master.
So, she took over. To an extent that I sometimes saw myself as a prisoner but I endured!
I saw myself like I had self-imprisoned myself
because something would tell me, "Go! This woman is not the right woman for you".
Okay, my daughter was still very young then.
My wife had to go home, from where I was born, a place called Tahu, Northwest.
She had to go and wean the child there until the child was old enough.
While she was in town, she befriended with some forces that were against me.
She even got close to my biological mother.
Every nonsense that she was told about me precipitated the anger and hatred against me.
When she came back from home, she never told me the journey from my own hometown.
She never told me anything.
But she was living life, suggesting that something bad must have been told to her.
Like my wife said,
I would be driving a motor vehicle on a public road,
my wife would start an argument, a small thing,
a little thing to her was to become a worst case scenario.
It would be blown out of proportion, a little thing; even if I tried to calm her down.
Now, she would be using her physicality.
I would be driving a car. She would be fighting for the steering wheel while the car was moving.
She would be struggling to disarm me, to take the firearm from my harness. This is the service pistol!
I have two firearms. I have a service pistol. I have a private firearm.
So, I'm always scared - whether I'm at work or not around at home.
She would be struggling to get possession of my firearm.
She would say, "Today, I'm going to kill you, you are dead.
After killing you, I'm going to kill myself".
She would be opening the car door while the car was in motion,
trying to jump out of the moving vehicle to commit suicide.
I said, "Oh my God, now if she jumps out of the moving vehicle,
it means the family, my in-laws will be pinning her death on me.
They won't see it as a suicide".
But I thank the God of Prophet T.B. Joshua because I prayed when I left my country.
I said, "God of Prophet T.B. Joshua, I know you will vindicate me in all this".
Mr Gideon Rapati & Wife
Deliverance Testimony
Indeed, children of God, as I'm standing here right now,
I feel I have got my freedom. I'm a free man now.
But my wife, who was manifesting - I know that demons were the ones who put me through long suffering.
The beauty standing here was not responsible; it was a demon.
Because this coward called demon, he does not come in one form.
He has so many forms; because he's a coward, he can't show himself.
He can use any form to come and mesmerize somebody's life.
It is true. My wife was always in a mood of fighting.
Five minutes!
I could never sit down with my wife, discuss anything pertaining to the household or the children.
Five minutes was enough, then she would just snap out of the blue.
She would be pointing fingers. She would become aggressive.
Even if I was trying to reason with her, my wife would be telling me,
"I'm not going to sit down and listen to this shit".
Telling me this straight to my face.
Remember this was the woman who would even want to pull my manhood.
I would be driving the car. She would then grab me in the front.
She would be beating me, using the palm of the hand, hit me hard try to take the firearm.
I would try to tend to the vehicle so that the vehicle wouldn't just go awry, with no control.
This was a woman who always accused me of cheating on her.
It is very painful when somebody accuses you of cheating, and yet, you know you're not cheating.
My wife would tell me straight, "You can pack your bags and go back to your ex", calling her by name.
She would even go to the extent of describing my ex.
Even before she met her, she would be describing how nice and caring she is.
There is no word my wife hasn't said to me.
Ugly words that will never go back.
You know, it is good now. I'm in the arena of liberty!
During my stay here, I have learned a lot about the art of forgiving.
To speak forgiveness, you are doing it for God, all glory goes to God.
Now, there is a confession that I want to make in this church.
The confession will shock my sisters and my brother at home in South Africa.
I didn't grow up with them. My mother gave me away when I was three months old.
She gave me to my aunt to raise me, so I grew up knowing my aunt as my mother.
I was perplexed when I turned 16 or 17 and people told me, "No, your mother is actually that one".
My mother did not give me away for any other reason than that she was struggling in life.
It was not deliberate.
So, when I came back home to join my real family,
some of my relatives just wanted to make me feel unwelcomed.
My heart was where I grew up.
So, when my wife was weaning the child at home,
I didn't know if my mom wanted to become frank or friendly to my wife (or not).
My mom told my wife that I had a sexually transmitted disease.
They call it 'drop' at home.
My wife never told me anything (about that conversation).
But whenever we finished having bedroom fun, she would jump up and go to clean herself.
I didn't know why. She would lie and say it's her culture. It's a culture thing from where she comes from.
Not knowing that she was cleaning herself up, so I couldn't infect her.
I met her six years later.
South Africa has the best hospitals.
I was cured of everything; I was clean.
One day, she told me it's my mom and my other relatives, that I am not going to mention, who told her.
I went to the hardware store and bought an axe!
I took it to those who do welding works to sharpen it. It was sharpened.
What I intended to do with the axe was to go home to attack my mother,
take a rope and hang myself, and my life would be finished.
Because I couldn't keep any women because of their interference.
But I have since forgiven my mother. After this I said, "I cannot do this to my mother because of a woman.
I cannot go to the extreme of doing that to my own mother. I have to forgive my mother.
I have to be friends with my mother".
I started experiencing a lot of love from my own mother. That was what unsettled my wife.
That was what made my wife accusing me of one thing or another.
Those things that I was not doing.
I found myself in an environment where I was reduced to a mere wife at home.
My wife works a twelve hour shift. I work only an eight hour shift.
So I'm the one who gets home early. I would be the one doing all the chores.
I would bathe the younger one, and I would help the other two to take their own baths.
I played the part of a mom, to an extent that my children saw me as a mother.
When I went to fetch my wife from work, my children would pass my wife, even if she was right in front of me.
My children would pass her and come to embrace me.
My children have the culture of hugging me.
All three of them would advance to me, pass their mother and come to embrace me.
Their mother would be saying, "Ah, they love you more than me". It's like there is no issue then.
Since I met my wife, one thing needs to be mentioned,
I experienced a lot of motor vehicle accidents.
Two with her. We cheated death.
Hitting a cattle - the two of us seated in the front - but the cattle flew over and I thank God for that.
I told myself that selling my car to pay for the trip to come to The SCOAN is worth while.
I told myself that the day I go, my problems will be things of the past.
A week prior to our trip to The SCOAN.
I never slept in the same room with my wife.
She was sleeping in the main bedroom. I was sleeping in my son's bedroom.
Before we came, on the same day that we had to depart from South Africa, my wife packed her bags.
There was no big argument.
She said she's leaving to go and cool herself off at her sister's place in another province.
Now, what I'm saying to the people of God, in general,
if a demon is involved, you won't see it, it does not come face to face with you.
My life experienced a downslope.
Financially, before I met her, I was able to pay my accounts. I was able to run my life.
When she came into my life, everything went down slope.
I am now in the deepest financial quagmire with a lot of financial institutions in South Africa.
And she also.
Because we live our lives on borrowed money. We live on credit.
So, brother, we want to find out from you now about
when you came and the man of God prayed for your wife.
Just tell us, when he prayed for your wife, what happened?
And ever since that day, what are the changes that you've seen in her and your life?
When the man of God prayed for my wife - in me, there was a mixed reaction of feelings.
I was overwhelmed. Something said to me, I must advance to the altar and claim that she's my wife.
But because of the order and organization in this place, I had to stay on my seat.
I was very happy because the fullness of light was now approaching the darkness,
that is why you saw my wife running away, because of her darkness.
Ever since then, you have been together for one week now.
What are the changes that you've seen in your life and marriage?
I have seen this beauty next to me falling in love with me all over again.
Mr Gideon Rapati & Wife
Deliverance Testimony
Now since my wife's deliverance, she's smiling back at me.
We are having civil, decent conversations.
We are even planning the life in Christ together.
That when we leave here, when we go back to our country, we are going to reflect Jesus Christ in us.
Mr Gideon Rapati & Wife
Deliverance Testimony
Hallelujah! Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ for this reconciliation!
You mean to say that now the affection is restored, you're now able to love your wife
and she's able to love you, something that has been missing from this marriage for 12 years?
All those things have come to bow down to the name Jesus.
Let me tell you something, children of God
This is my experience.
I would be enduring that long-suffering, not knowing that I only had to run to one man called Jesus Christ.
At work, my colleagues and my friends, I didn't know that when I approached them to seek advice,
immediately after I had left, they would make a meal out of it.
I would become breakfast, lunch and supper for them.
I would become a laughingstock, a joke and everything you can think of.
I didn't know that all my problems, all I had to do was to take them to Jesus Christ
because He said, all your burdens are My burdens.
Wow. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
We give glory to God once again,
and finally, sir, what is your advice to our viewers around the world?
Alright.
Viewers, I stand in front of you to declare and to decree to you that
there is only one Man who can bring solutions to your life.
Like I have said, don't seek advice. Don't even narrate your own life to anybody.
Everything! Hardships, setbacks and everything!
Whether you are fighting with your wife. Whether your marital life is not a bed full of roses.
Run to God because God will never laugh at your problem.
Hallelujah! Thank You, Jesus!
Just finally from our sister, your final word of advice to our viewers around the world.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
Thank You, Jesus.
The advice for people all over the world is that
when you are facing some challenges with your husband,
don't go to traditional healers, they don't have a solution.
I know it from my own experience
because I was going from one traditional healer to another.
You would pay. I didn't mind to pay 3000 or 5000.
What they would do to your body - hey!
They would cut your body all over; you would think that cutting your body was the solution.
I didn't know that they were putting a lot of spirits in my body to see myself as a man.
So what I am saying now is that
you know when you go from one traditional healer to another,
I was experiencing a lot of things, I was seeing things
without my husband telling me or anyone telling me.
I would tell him, "You are doing this, you are doing that".
I would find out that those things were true. And no one had to tell me about those things.
I was just dreaming it. It's because of devil, it's because of satan.
Satan was giving me all those dreams. So that I had to keep on fighting, keep on fighting.
Men all over the world, be supportive to your wife. Thank you!
Mrs Yvonne Rapati & Husband
Deliverance Testimony